<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Animated Symbols on MAP-VERSE</title><link>https://MAP-VERSE.github.io/Repository/tags/animated-symbols/</link><description>Recent content in Animated Symbols on MAP-VERSE</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://MAP-VERSE.github.io/Repository/tags/animated-symbols/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fixations &amp; Saccades metadata</title><link>https://MAP-VERSE.github.io/Repository/post/dataset09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://MAP-VERSE.github.io/Repository/post/dataset09/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.mdpi.com/2220-9964/13/4/118">The primary objective of this study is to assess how the motion of dynamic point symbols impacts preattentive processing on a map. Specifically, it involves identifying the motion velocity parameters for cartographic animated pictorial symbols that contribute to the preattentive perception of the target symbols. We created five pictorial symbols, each accompanied by a unique animation tailored to convey the meaning associated with each symbol. The animation dynamics of symbols on the administrative map were distributed across arithmetic, logarithmic, and exponential scales. Eye-tracking technology was utilized to explain the user’s visual attention. The key findings reveal that, although movement does not uniformly hold the same designation in cartographic communication, it could guide user attention to identify the value peaks in quantitative map visualization. Motion velocity enhances the salience of animated symbols, making them stand out, not only against static elements but also against other animated distractors. Additionally, motion distributions between symbol classes based on exponential or arithmetic scales were identified as the most successful. Nevertheless, certain types of motion, such as rotational, do not perform well with pictorial symbols, even on the most effective motion distribution scale.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>

&lt;link rel="stylesheet" href="https://MAP-VERSE.github.io/Repository/css/hugo-easy-gallery.css" />

&lt;div class="gallery caption-position-bottom caption-effect-fade hover-effect-zoom hover-transition" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageGallery">
	 


&lt;/div>

&lt;h5 id="full-citation-dataset-with-doi">Full citation (dataset) with DOI&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Cybulski, Paweł, 2023, &amp;ldquo;Fixations &amp;amp; Saccades metadata (NCN SONATA 16 &amp;ldquo;Preattentive attributes of dynamic point symbols in quantitative mapping&amp;rdquo;)&amp;rdquo;, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.7910/DVN/YHYXLI">https://doi.org/10.7910/DVN/YHYXLI&lt;/a>, Harvard Dataverse, V1&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="related-articles">Related articles&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Cybulski P. Animating Cartographic Meaning: Unveiling the Impact of Pictorial Symbol Motion Speed in Preattentive Processing. ISPRS International Journal of Geo-Information. 2024; 13(4):118. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/ijgi13040118">https://doi.org/10.3390/ijgi13040118&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="related-links">Related links&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.mdpi.com/2220-9964/13/4/118">https://www.mdpi.com/2220-9964/13/4/118&lt;/a>&lt;/p>


&lt;div class="box" >
 &lt;figure itemprop="associatedMedia" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject">
 &lt;div class="img">
 &lt;img itemprop="thumbnail" src="https://MAP-VERSE.github.io/Repository/Repository/img/img09.jpg" alt="/Repository/img/img09.jpg"/>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;a href="https://MAP-VERSE.github.io/Repository/Repository/img/img09.jpg" itemprop="contentUrl">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/figure>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>