<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Daily Smartphone Usage on MAP-VERSE</title><link>https://MAP-VERSE.github.io/Repository/tags/daily-smartphone-usage/</link><description>Recent content in Daily Smartphone Usage on MAP-VERSE</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://MAP-VERSE.github.io/Repository/tags/daily-smartphone-usage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rymarkiewicz et al. (2024)</title><link>https://MAP-VERSE.github.io/Repository/post/dataset08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://MAP-VERSE.github.io/Repository/post/dataset08/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.mdpi.com/2220-9964/13/2/42">This study investigated the impact of smartphone usage frequency on the effectiveness and accuracy of symbol location in a variety of spatial contexts on mobile maps using eye-tracking technology while utilizing the example of Mapy.cz. The scanning speed and symbol detection were also considered. The use of mobile applications for navigation is discussed, emphasizing their popularity and convenience of use. The importance of eye tracking as a valuable tool for testing the usability of cartographic products, enabling the assessment of users’ visual strategies and their ability to memorize information, was highlighted. The frequency of smartphone use has been shown to be an important factor in users’ ability to locate symbols in different spatial contexts. Everyday smartphone users have shown higher accuracy and efficiency in image processing, suggesting a potential link between habitual smartphone use and increased efficiency in mapping tasks. Participants who were dissatisfied with the legibility of a map looked longer at the symbols, suggesting that they put extra cognitive effort into decoding the symbols. In the present study, gender differences in pupil size were also observed during the study. Women consistently showed a larger pupil diameter, potentially indicating greater cognitive load on the participants.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>

&lt;link rel="stylesheet" href="https://MAP-VERSE.github.io/Repository/css/hugo-easy-gallery.css" />

&lt;div class="gallery caption-position-bottom caption-effect-fade hover-effect-zoom hover-transition" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageGallery">
	 


&lt;/div>

&lt;h5 id="full-citation-dataset-with-doi">Full citation (dataset) with DOI&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Horbiński, Tymoteusz, 2024, &amp;ldquo;Efficiency and accuracy in locating symbols within diverse spatial contexts on mobile maps using eye-tracking technology on the example of the Mapy.cz&amp;rdquo;, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.7910/DVN/DZUFJ1">https://doi.org/10.7910/DVN/DZUFJ1&lt;/a>, Harvard Dataverse, V1&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="related-articles">Related articles&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Rymarkiewicz W, Cybulski P, Horbiński T. Measuring Efficiency and Accuracy in Locating Symbols on Mobile Maps Using Eye Tracking. ISPRS International Journal of Geo-Information. 2024; 13(2):42. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/ijgi13020042">https://doi.org/10.3390/ijgi13020042&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="related-links">Related links&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.mdpi.com/2220-9964/13/2/42">https://www.mdpi.com/2220-9964/13/2/42&lt;/a>


&lt;div class="box" >
 &lt;figure itemprop="associatedMedia" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject">
 &lt;div class="img">
 &lt;img itemprop="thumbnail" src="https://MAP-VERSE.github.io/Repository/Repository/img/img08.jpg" alt="/Repository/img/img08.jpg"/>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;a href="https://MAP-VERSE.github.io/Repository/Repository/img/img08.jpg" itemprop="contentUrl">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/figure>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>