<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lab-Based and Online User Studies on MAP-VERSE</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/Repository/tags/lab-based-and-online-user-studies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lab-Based and Online User Studies on MAP-VERSE</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/Repository/tags/lab-based-and-online-user-studies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>EyeMouseMap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Repository/post/dataset06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Repository/post/dataset06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://eurocarto2024.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/EC24_workshop_online-user-experiments_proceedings.pdf#page=9&#34;&gt;The examination of both perceptual and cognitive issues related to map reading requires the performance of experimental procedures that aim to measure map user response under free viewing or task-oriented conditions. Map user reaction can be modeled by considering data collected utilizing several experimental techniques (e.g., reaction time and response accuracy measurements). However, it is of great importance to explore experimental frameworks that can be executed remotely. The present study aims to present a work in progress that aims to compare gaze and cursor activity during the execution of a typical map reading task. In more detail, we implement a lab-based experiment which concurrently captures both eye and (computer) mouse movements while searching for specific point symbols on cartographic backgrounds. The experiment is based on the use of the visual stimuli and point target symbols presented by Pappa &amp;amp; Krassanakis (2022). The aforementioned study was implemented utilizing remote (online) mouse tracking techniques. In the framework of the current work, the overarching goal is to explore quantitative measures that are able to describe individual and/or aggregated visual search behavioral differences. Considering the aggregated statistical grayscale heatmaps produced by both experimental studies, we plan to use the Jaccard index, the Dice coefficient and the BF score in order to perform comparisons between gaze and cursor activity, as well as between the mouse movement data produced under both conditions (lab-based and online). In addition, we will compute the GraphGazeD (Liaskos &amp;amp; Krassanakis, 2024) metric towards describing existing visual perception differences. The process of data analysis will be fully automatized using Python programming language and MATLAB software.&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/Repository/css/hugo-easy-gallery.css&#34; /&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;gallery caption-position-bottom caption-effect-fade hover-effect-zoom hover-transition&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageGallery&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#x9;  &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;full-citation-dataset-with-doi&#34;&gt;Full citation (dataset) with DOI&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vlachou, A., Pappa, A., Liaskos, D., &amp;amp; Krassanakis, V. (2024). EyeMouseMap [Data set]. Zenodo. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.13929730&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.13929730&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;related-articles&#34;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vlachou A., Liaskos, D., &amp;amp; Krassanakis, V. (2024). Quantifying map user response differences between gaze and cursor activity during searching cartographic point symbols. Online User Experiments: Seeing What Map Users See without Seeing Them (Pre-conference Workshop, EuroCarto 2024). Available at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://eurocarto2024.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/EC24_workshop_online-user-experiments_proceedings.pdf#page=9&#34;&gt;https://eurocarto2024.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/EC24_workshop_online-user-experiments_proceedings.pdf#page=9&lt;/a&gt; Pappa, A., &amp;amp;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Krassanakis, V. (2022). Examining the preattentive effect on cartographic backgrounds utilizing remote mouse tracking. Abstracts of the ICA, 5, 111. (EuroCarto 2022 Conference). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5194/ica-abs-5-111-2022&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5194/ica-abs-5-111-2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;related-links&#34;&gt;Related links&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5194/ica-abs-5-111-2022&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5194/ica-abs-5-111-2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;box&#34; &gt;&#xA;  &lt;figure  itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;img itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/Repository/Open-Metadata-Platform-for-Map-Usability_v2/img/img06.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;/Open-Metadata-Platform-for-Map-Usability_v2/img/img06.jpg&#34;/&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/Repository/Open-Metadata-Platform-for-Map-Usability_v2/img/img06.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
